Ethnic Heritage and Language Schools in America Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Ethnic Heritage and Language Schools in America Project collection 1982-1986
AFC 1993/001
Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress), collector
American Folklife Center, sponsor
18990 items; 24 boxes; 9.6 linear feet.
25 boxes.
299 sound cassettes: analog.
60 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
24 sound tape reels: analog; 5 in.
1130 slides: color; 35 mm.
9072 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 35 mm.
1 videocassette (UCA 30); 3/4 in.
4 reels: black and white.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection consists of field notes, interviews, curriculum materials, sound recordings, photographs, and one videorecording resulting from a survey conducted by the American Folklife Center, Library of Congress in 1982 which documented 23 ethnic schools in the United States. Fieldwork was conducted at various locations including: Armenian school in Watertown, Massachusetts; Cambodian school in Houston, Texas; Chinese school in San Antonio, Texas; Czech school in Cedar Rapids, Iowa; Dutch school in Pella, Iowa; German-Russian school in Strasburg, North Dakota; Greek school in Birmingham, Alabama; Greek school in Buffalo, New York; Hebrew school in Nashville, Tennessee; Hungarian school in New Brunswick, New Jersey; Hupa language school in Hoopa Valley, California; Islamic school in Seattle, Washington; Japanese school in Los Angeles, California; Korean school in Silver Spring, Maryland; Latvian school in Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Lebanese school in Birmingham, Alabama; Polish school in Chicago, Illinois; Portuguese school in Taunton, Massachusetts; Turkish school in New York, N.Y.; Ukrainian school in Woonsocket, Rhode Island; and the East Harlem Music School in New York, N.Y.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Arocho, Rudy; Baird, Scott J., 1939-; Basa, Peter, 1935-; Bell, Carole O.; Bradunas, Elena; Bromberg, Joann Berlin; Cech, Barbara; Conklin, Nancy Faires; Davis, Lee (Anthropologist); Deak, Frank; Dwyer-Shick, Susan; Fast, Jana; Feintuch, Burt, 1949-2018; Fish, Lydia M.; Fleischhauer, Carl; Gates, Bob, 1950-; Haas, Mary-Louise; Kloberdanz, Timothy J.; Leung, John; Long, Lucy M., 1956-; Marks, Morton; McCallum, Brenda; McClain, Margy; Miller, Jefferson; Nagy, Susan Mary; Penti, Marsha Elizabeth, 1945-; Proschan, Frank; Sacks, Maurie; Seipel, Sandy; Skillman, Amy E.; Tarhan, Lance; Topping, Brett, 1947-; Vidutis, Richard, 1945-; Webber, Philip E., 1944-; Westover, Victoria, 1958-
Organizations
American Folklife Center; Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress)
Subjects
Arab Americans--Education.; Armenian Americans--Education.; Buddhist education--United States.; Cambodian Americans--Education.; Caribbean Americans--Education.; Chinese Americans--Education.; Christian education--United States.; Czech Americans--Education.; Dutch Americans--Education.; Education--Curricula--United States.; Ethiopian Americans--Education.; Ethnic arts--Study and teaching--United States.; Ethnic schools--United States.; Ethnicity in children--United States.; Folk dancing--Study and teaching.; Folklore and education--United States.; Greek Americans--Education.; Hispanic Americans--Education.; Hungarian Americans--Education.; Hupa Indians--Education.; Islamic education--United States.; Japanese Americans--Education.; Jewish religious education--United States.; Jews--United States--Education.; Korean Americans--Education.; Language schools--United States.; Latvian Americans--Education.; Lebanese Americans--Education.; Lithuanian Americans--Education.; Minorities--Education--United States.; Minorities--United States--Language.; Polish Americans--Education.; Portuguese Americans--Education.; Religious education--United States.; Turkish Americans--Education.; Ukrainian Americans--Education.
Titles
Ethnic heritage and language schools in America.; Also known as: Ethnic schools project
Form/Genre
Ethnography.; Field notes.; Field recordings.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Microfilms.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Arrangement
Organized by series according to each school with additional series for administrative and additional materials. The slides and photographs originally in Boxes 23-28 were rehoused and moved offsite; these box numbers are no longer in use.
Acquisition
Accessioned; 198?
Separated Material
Some manuscript material, including correspondence, field notes, contributor forms, sound recording logs, and transcripts were microfilmed and the originals were not retained. See PDF for full microfilm inventory.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access restrictions apply; some or all content is stored offsite. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Other Format
Four microfilm reels of a portion of the manuscript project materials have also been cataloged separately: Microfilm 95/4760 (L) with viewing copies available in the Folklife Reading Room.
Bibliography
Fourteen of the schools are represented in the book which resulted from this survey: Bradunas, Elena and Topping, Brett, eds. Ethnic heritage and language schools in America. Washington, D.C.: American Folklife Center, Library of Congress, 1988.
Administrative History
The project has its inspirational roots in the American Folklife Center's 1977 Chicago Ethnic Arts Project, as well as in the scholarly writings of sociolinguist Joshua A. Fishman. During the spring of 1982, the project was set in motion by Center staff member Elena Bradunas to "try to understand the complex nature of ethnic identity and delineate the cultural, historical, and social referents by which the group identifies itself." Twenty-one primary fieldworkers were selected, two of which had one co-worker assisting. All but two of these 23 have their curriculum vitae or resume on file (see Correspondence). Of the 22 groups, 14 are represented in the resulting book, Ethnic Heritage and Language Schools in America.
The fieldworkers, followed by their respective ethnic group focus, were: Scott Baird (Chinese), Carole O. Bell (Ukrainian), Elena Bradunas (Ethiopian and Lithuanian), JoAnn Bromberg (Armenian), Lee Davis (Hupa Indian), Susan Dwyer-Shick (Islamic), Jana Fast (Czechoslovakian), Burt Feintuch (Hebrew), Lydia Fish (Greek, NY), Timothy J. Kloberdanz (German-Russian), Lucy Long (Korean), Morton Marks (Urban Caribbean/Hispanic), Brenda McCallum (Lebanese and Greek), Margy McClain (Polish), Susan Nagy (Hungarian), Marsha Penti (Portuguese), Frank Proschan (Cambodian), Maurie Sacks (Turkish), Amy E. Skillman (Japanese), Ričardas Vidutis (Latvian), Phil Webber (Dutch). In addition to the aforementioned fieldworkers, Nancy Conklin assisted Brenda McCallum in studying the Lebanese and Greek schools in Birmingham, Alabama, and Mary-Louise Haas assisted Carole O. Bell with the study of the Ukrainian school.
Three individuals served as consultants to the project: Dr. Joshua A. Fishman, who was consulted regarding sociolinguistics; Ewa Hauser, who supplemented the study of the Polish school by conducting an independent study of Polish curriculum materials; Dr. Richard Hulan, who was consulted on ethnic schools in general.
Fieldwork consisted of a commitment of at least three site visits to a fieldworker's respective ethnic school over a three month period, between April and July 1982. While most of the fieldwork was finished by the summer of 1982, the final papers went through a series of editing up through September of 1986. Elena Bradunas left the project after the first round of editing, after which Brett Topping assumed the editing role. Long reports were shortened and standardized for the purpose of publishing. Both long and short versions of the fieldworkers' reports have been retained in both the microfilmed and unmicrofilmed format.
While the majority of the fieldworkers did their own photography, seven were assisted by one or two others. Supplementary photographers include: Rudy Arocho (Chinese), Peter Basa (Hungarian), Barbara Cech (Dutch), Frank Deak, Jr. (Hungarian), Carl Fleischhauer (Ethiopian and Lithuanian), Bob Gates (Hebrew), John Leung, Jr. (Chinese), Sandy Seipel (Hupa Indian), and Vicky Westover (Armenian).
Scope and Content
The Ethnic Heritage and Language Schools in America Project Collection (also called the Ethnic Schools Project) represents 22 ethnic groups: Armenian, Cambodian, Chinese, Czechoslovakian, Dutch, Ethiopian, German-Russian, two different Greek communities, Hebrew, Hungarian, Hupa Indian, Islamic, Japanese, Korean, Latvian, Lebanese, Lithuanian, Polish, Portuguese, Turkish, Ukrainian, and Urban Caribbean/Hispanic.
The collection consists of field notes, interviews, curriculum materials, sound recordings, photographs, and one videorecording resulting from a survey conducted by the American Folklife Center, Library of Congress in 1982 which documented 23 ethnic schools in the United States. Fieldwork was conducted at various locations including: Armenian school in Watertown, Massachusetts; Cambodian school in Houston, Texas; Chinese school in San Antonio, Texas; Czech school in Cedar Rapids, Iowa; Dutch school in Pella, Iowa; German-Russian school in Strasburg, North Dakota; Greek school in Birmingham, Alabama; Greek school in Buffalo, New York; Hebrew school in Nashville, Tennessee; Hungarian school in New Brunswick, New Jersey; Hupa language school in Hoopa Valley, California; Islamic school in Seattle, Washington; Japanese school in Los Angeles, California; Korean school in Silver Spring, Maryland; Latvian school in Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Lebanese school in Birmingham, Alabama; Polish school in Chicago, Illinois; Portuguese school in Taunton, Massachusetts; Turkish school in New York, N.Y.; Ukrainian school in Woonsocket, Rhode Island; and the East Harlem Music School in New York, N.Y.
Approximately 200 individuals were interviewed. On the average a fieldworker interviewed nine informants, though four groups do not list the number of their informants. The interviews were to focus on the school's history, financing, administrative concerns, curriculum, teachers, parents, and children.
Fieldworkers took photographs and slides of the schools and collected curriculum materials. While the bulk of this material was made up of textbooks, other items were included, such as: flash cards, calendars, workbooks, mimeographed sheets from homemade notebooks, and an 80-slide carousel with accompanying tape cassette. Miscellaneous photos were also donated by five schools ranging from a few class photos to a 3-ring notebook full of black and white as well as color photos from the Hungarian school.
Container List
See PDF for more detailed inventory of manuscripts and materials copied to microfilm, which includes correspondence, fieldnotes, sound recording logs, titles of curriculum materials and names of interviewees.
- Series 1: Administrative
  - Contents (Box 1)
  - Introductory Materials (Box 1)
  - Introduction to Elena Bradunas and the project (Box 1)
  - Original draft of inventory (Box 1)
  - Consultancy with Dr. Joshua A. Fishman (Box 1)
  - Consultancy with Dr. Richard Hulan (Box 1)
  - Ethnic curriculum materials (7 folders) (Box 1)
  - Project abstract (Box 1)
  - Draft proposals (Box 1)
  - Project calendars (Box 1)
  - Project announcements (Box 1)
  - Addresses of fieldworkers (Box 1)
  - Chart and lists of fieldworkers and schools (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Responsibilities of fieldworkers (Box 1)
  - “Some things considered...” by Elena Bradunas (Box 1)
  - Organizing and numbering field documentation (Box 1)
  - Photography advice (Box 1)
  - Budget and expenditures (Box 1)
  - Assessment workshop (held August 26 and 27, 1982) (Box 1)
  - Overall project expenditures-summary (Box 1)
  - Project synopsis (Box 1)
  - Request for transfer of documents (Box 1)
  - Photograph and audio logs, 9 5 1⁄4 -inch floppy discs (Box 1)
  - “Calendar” notes in a spiral steno pad (Box 2)
  - Sound recording tape inventory (Box 2)
  - Notes on relevant materials in WPA files (Box 2)
  - Photo inventory and inventory of mailing packets sent to AFC (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous copies of photos from miscellaneous sources (Box 2)
  - Book, Ethnic Heritage and Language Schools in America (1988) (Box 2)
  - Microfilmed material (Reel 1)
- Series 2: The Armenian General Benevolent Union (AGBU) Armenian Elementary School, Watertown, Massachusetts (Fieldworkers JoAnn Bromberg and Vicky Westover)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 3)
    - Photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 3)
    - Curriculum materials (Box 3)
    - Curriculum materials from the Armenian Relief Society (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Curriculum materials from the Armenian Relief Society (Box 4)
    - Publications and news clippings (Box 4)
    - Final reports (Box 4)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 1)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, May 12-June 30, 1982, 16 sound cassettes; AFS 23,359-AFS 23,374
    - Sounds of Armenia, A.R.S. Armenian Ethnic Heritage Project, Armenian Relief Society, copyright 1976, 1 audiocassette; AFC 1993/001: SR01
    - “They Came from Ararat”, 1 audiocassette; AFC 1993/001: SR02
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, June 1982, 77 slides
    - Black and white negatives, May 15-June 16, 1982, 10 rolls (5 roles are missing)
    - Enlargements, 10 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 3)
    - Class picture, 1 color print (8 x 10 inch) (Box 3)
    - “They Came from Ararat”: Curriculum materials from the Armenian Relief Society, 80 slides (some in color) (Box 4)
- Series 3: The Cambodian/Khmer School, Houston, Texas (Fieldworker Frank Proschan)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 4)
    - Photo logs and corresponding contact sheets for black and white photographs (Box 4)
    - Final reports (Box 4)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 2)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 20-June 12, 1982, 13 sound cassettes; AFS 23,375-AFS 23,387
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, April 24-June 11, 1982, 74 slides
    - Black and white negatives, April 24-June 13, 1982, 21 rolls
    - Enlargements, 12 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 4)
- Series 4: The Chinese School of San Antonio, Texas (Fieldworkers Scott Baird and Rudy Arocha)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 5)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Final reports (Box 5)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 2)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 20-May 21, 1982, 10 7-inch reels; AFS 23,401-AFS 23,410
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, April 23, 1982, 27 slides
    - Black and white negatives, April 20-June 24, 1982, 7 rolls
    - Enlargements, 2 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 5)
- Series 5: The Czech School, Cedar Rapids, Iowa (Fieldworker Jana Fast)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 5)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 5)
    - Curriculum materials (items 1-3 of 6) (Box 5)
    - Curriculum materials (items 4-6 of 6) (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, folder 1 of 2 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, folder 2 of 2 (oversize) (Box 34)
    - Final reports (Box 5)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 2)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, June 17-July 2, 1982, 8 7-inch reels; AFS 23,411-AFS 23,418
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, July 2, 1982, 14 slides
    - Black and white negatives, June 29, 1982, 1 roll
- Series 6: Pella Christian Grade School [Dutch], Pella, Iowa (Fieldworkers Philip Webber and Barbara Cech)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 6)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 6)
    - Curriculum materials (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Final reports (Box 6)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 3)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 29-July 29, 1982, 20 7-inch reels; AFS 23,424-AFS 23,423
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, May 6-June 1982, 166 slides
    - Black and white negatives, May 6-July 1982, 29 rolls
    - Enlargements, 7 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 6)
- Series 7: German-Russian Ethnic Studies at Emmons Central High School, Strasburg, North Dakota (Fieldworker Timothy J. Kloberdanz)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 7)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 7)
    - Final reports (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 3)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, March-June 8, 1982, 10 7-inch reels; AFS 23,454-AFS 23,463
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, April 28-June 9, 1982, 85 slides
    - Black and white negatives, April 13-June 9, 1982, 7 rolls
    - Enlargements, 3 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 7)
- Series 8: The Greek School at the Hellenic Orthodox Church of the Annunciation, Buffalo, New York (Fieldworker Lydia Fish)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 7)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Final reports (Box 7)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 3)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 24-July 12, 1982, 20 7-inch reels; AFS 23,464-AFS 23,483
  - Graphic Images
    - Black and white negatives, May 2-July 25, 1982, 16 rolls
    - Enlargements, 4 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 7)
- Series 9: The West End Synagogue [Hebrew], Nashville, Tennessee (Fieldworker Burt Feintuch)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 7)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 7)
    - Curriculum materials (Box 7)
    - Publications, news clippings, etc. (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Final reports (Box 7)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 4)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 18-May 12, 1982, 14 7-inch reels; AFS 23,554-AFS 23,567
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, May 2, 1982, 31 slides
    - Black and white negatives, April 18-May 12, 1982, 8 rolls
    - Enlargements, 4 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 7)
- Series 10: Hétvégi Magyar Iskola és Óvoda Hungarian Saturday Classes and Kindergarten, New Brunswick, New Jersey (Susan Nagy)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 8)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 8)
    - Photograph inventory and corresponding contact sheets (Appendix IX) (Box 8)
    - Appendix V: graduation materials and yearbooks (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Curriculum reading materials (4 folders) (Box 8)
    - Published materials, news clippings, pamphlets, etc. (Box 8)
    - Appendix X: supplementary materials (Box 8)
    - 11 publications (not in folders) (Box 9)
    - Final reports (Box 9)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 4)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 24-June 8, 1982, 15 sound cassettes; AFS 23,494-AFS 23,508
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, May 1-22, 1982, 61 slides
    - Black and white negatives, May 22, 1982, 2 rolls
    - Enlargement, 1 black and white print (8 x 10 inch) (Box 8)
    - Photograph album, 1974-1980, Photocopies of approximately 100 black and white and color photographs (various size) (Box 33)
- Series 11: Hupa Indian Language Schools, Hoopa, California (Fieldworkers Lee Davis and Sandy Seipel)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 10)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 10)
    - Final reports (Box 10)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 4)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, June 3-July 1, 1982, 11 sound cassettes; AFS 23,509-AFS 23,519
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, June 17-July 1, 1982, 58 slides
    - Black and white negatives, May 24-July 1, 1982, 4 rolls
    - Enlargement, 1 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 10)
- Series 12: The Islamic School of Seattle (ISS), Seattle, Washington (Fieldworker Susan Dwyer-Shick)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 10)
    - Photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 10)
    - Class pictures, 4 7 x 7 inch color prints (Box 10)
    - Curriculum materials (Box 10)
    - Publications, news clippings, etc. (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Final reports (Box 10)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 5)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, May 5-June 10, 1982, 22 sound cassettes; AFS 23,520-AFS 23,530; AFc 1993/001 SR03-13
  - Graphic Images
    - Black and white negatives, May 12-June 24, 1982, 12 rolls
    - Enlargements, 5 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 10)
- Series 13: The Senshin Gakuin and the Dharma School of the Senshin Buddhist Church of Los Angeles, California [Japanese Buddhists] (Fieldworker Amy E. Skillman)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 11)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Curriculum materials (Box 11)
    - Final reports (Box 11)
    - Dharma School Teacher's Guide (Box 33)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 5)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, May 15-June 19, 1982, 23 sound cassettes; AFS 23,531-AFS 23,553
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, May 8-July 17, 1982, 63 sllides
    - Black and white negatives, May 27-June 10, 1982, 6 rolls
    - Enlargements, 2 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 11)
- Series 14: The First Korean School, Silver Spring, Maryland (Fieldworker Lucy Long)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 11)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 11)
    - Curriculum materials (Box 11)
    - Children's serial, 12 volumes (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Final reports (Box 12)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 5)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, March 13-June 19, 1982, 29 7-inch reels; AFS 23,568-AFS 23,596
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, April 24-May 15, 1982, 90 slides
    - Black and white negatives, Fall 1981-June 19, 1982, 27 rolls
    - Enlargements, 10 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 11)
- Series 15: Oskars Kalpaks Latvian Saturday School, Wauwatosa, Wisconsin (Fieldworker Ričardas (Richard) Vidutis)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 12)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Final reports (Box 12)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 6)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, May 8-June 10, 1982, 37 sound cassettes; AFS 23,597-AFS 23,633
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, May 23-June 12, 1982, 67 slides
    - Black and white negatives, April 24-June 10, 1982, 17 rolls
    - Enlargements, 8 black and white prints (8 x 10 inch) (Box 12)
- Series 16: The Lebanese Arabic School and The Greek School, Birmingham, Alabama (Fieldworkers Brenda McCallum and Nancy Conklin)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 13)
    - Slides and photos and corresponding contact sheets (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Supplementary materials (Box 13)
    - Final reports (Box 13)
    - Microfilmed material (Reel 6)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Interviews, April 20-June 9, 1982, 16 sound cassettes; AFS 23,634-AFS 23,639
  - Graphic Images
    - Slides, April 28-May 12, 1982, 36 slides
    - Black and white negatives, April 28-June 9, 1982, 10 rolls
    - Enlargement, 1 black and white print (8 x 10 inch) (Box 13)
- Series 17: General Casimir Pulaski Polish School, Chicago, Illinois (Fieldworker Margy McClain)
  - Manuscripts
    - Contents (Box 13)
    - Slide and photo logs and corresponding contact sheets (Box 13)
    - Curriculum materials, Item A.1 (Box 13)
    - 12 publications/primers in Polish (Box 13)
    - Curriculum materials, Item A.1B (Box 14)
    - 11 publications/primers in Polish (Box 14)
    - 5 publications in Polish (Box 15)
    - 2 publications in Polish (Box 16)
    - Curriculum materials, Item A.28 through Item A.30 (Box 16)
    - 6 publications in Polish (Box 16)
    - Curriculum materials, C.1 through C.4. (Box 16)